<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Atlas | Ivan Porto Carrero]]></title>
  <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/categories/atlas/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-23T23:03:37+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://flanders.co.nz/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ivan Porto Carrero]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boo, Ironpython, Scriptaculous, MS Ajax and me]]></title>
    <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/2006/11/07/boo-ironpython-scriptaculous-ms-ajax-and-me/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-07T07:16:53+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flanders.co.nz/2006/11/07/boo-ironpython-scriptaculous-ms-ajax-and-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the weekend I got the idea of learning ironpython by moving the codebase that I have for nblogr to <a href="http://www.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?ProjectName=IronPython">ironpython</a> script and compiling it.</p>

<p>Everything went fine until I had to decorate a method to make it cache/participate in a transaction/set a layout on a controller because ironpython in all its beauty doesn't support attributes on methods or classes.</p>

<p>I'm also missing a reference for <a href="http://www.codeplex.com/Wiki/View.aspx?ProjectName=IronPython">ironpython</a>. Something that shows the available functions and the syntax for inheritance etc.  which slowed me down of course.</p>

<p>Why do I want a dynamic language ?</p>

<p>The 2 main reasons are : <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duck_typing">Duck typing</a> and readable <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anonymous_closure">anonymous functions</a>.  In c# there is the concept of anonymous delegates but that code really looks like it has been hit by a train, ugly.</p>

<p>I've been writing in <a href="http://boo.codehaus.org/">boo</a> for a while now just as a templating language and yes I like <a href="http://boo.codehaus.org/">boo</a> a lot.  It combines the nice features of python with the c# language in a wrist friendly way. (I never got the point of wrist friendly thing until I got <a href="http://www.ninds.nih.gov/disorders/carpal_tunnel/detail_carpal_tunnel.htm#69013049">carpal tunnel syndrome</a>, now it suddenly is a major issue)</p>

<p>I sure wish there would be a language service for visual studio to do boo development but I've been using sharp develop 2.1 to check it out.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.sharpdevelop.com/">SharpDevelop 2.1</a> is a nice piece of work definitely for an open source IDE', it beats eclipse in my book</p>

<p>In boo everything is an object also your functions and expressions (read it has anonymous functions).  Boo is strong typed but mimics duck typing in some form.</p>

<p>To conclude this little intermezzo : my next project will be written in boo :)</p>

<p>On the ajax library front I would have to report that I haven 't looked at atlas/ms ajax since the beginning of september . I had decided to use it again when they finally release the framework.  So I've been checking out these other libraries that are out there.  I checked out <a href="http://jquery.com">jquery</a> which is a cool library but it is also slower in execution than the other ones.</p>

<p>The next one on the list was <a href="http://script.aculo.us">scriptaculous</a> and that is the one I've been using in my projects now.  Scriptaculous does exactly what is expected and uses the javascript prototype model which happens to be one i like :)</p>

<p>The move from the guys at MS to make their ajax extensions based on prototype was surprising but very positive in my book :) So when they release it i'll look at creating an javascript provider for nblogr so that you would be able to switch between your favourite library (we have plans to support the major libraries out of the  box.) </p>

<p>del.icio.us tags: <a href="http://del.icio.us/popular/Boo">Boo</a>, <a href="http://del.icio.us/popular/IronPython">IronPython</a>, <a href="http://del.icio.us/popular/Programming">Programming</a>, <a href="http://del.icio.us/popular/General">General</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preview release of NBlogr]]></title>
    <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/2006/09/02/preview-release-of-nblogr/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-02T23:30:22+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flanders.co.nz/2006/09/02/preview-release-of-nblogr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I put a preview release of NBlogr online.</p>

<p>I still have to change the online site but will do so very shortly.</p>

<p>This release has very basic functionality and is not yet feature complete so a lot may change later on.</p>

<p>If anybody feels like joining the project do not hesitate :) All help I get is extremely welcome.</p>

<pre><code>            [http://www.codeplex.com/Release/ProjectReleases.aspx?ProjectName=Nblogr](http://www.codeplex.com/Release/ProjectReleases.aspx?ProjectName=Nblogr)
</code></pre>

<p>I'm heading into a very busy week/couple of weeks so I'm not sure if I will be able to spend as much time as I've been spending lately on the project.  But I think every week I will be able to show some progress at least.</p>

<p>If you feel like it go ahead and give it a try but don't upgrade your blog just yet :).</p>

<p>I'd be keen to know what your thoughts are on the subject.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FileUploading for NBlogr]]></title>
    <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/2006/09/01/fileuploading-for-nblogr/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-01T09:13:37+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flanders.co.nz/2006/09/01/fileuploading-for-nblogr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To upload files in nblogr. I wanted the user to have the possibility to upload as many files as they wanted but only show one file element.</p>

<p>The upload procedure has to work without reloading the page entirely but there is no way of getting the size or the bytes of a file through the html input file control from clientscript without popping up a security warning.<br/>
And what do I personally think about security warnings : they are a necessary evil but limit you a lot in the development of contemporary sites with rich client interaction.<br/>
If I am to present a site to my parents and they have to figure stuff out themselves I'm pretty sure that once the read the words : Security warning, Potential risk etc... they will click no ==> site doesn't work ==> site == crap</p>

<p>I wanted to include an upload with progress bar but decided to let that idea go and just give an implementation of a multiple file upload with a single inputelement. Maybe I will put this in during the next iteration. That way I can probably release a ctp this weekend and start thinking about a plugin architecture (thanks for the idea <a href="http://blog.bluecog.co.nz/">JD</a>)</p>

<p>Because of the file issues i have to run it in an iframe :-s and have the page and the frame talk to eachother.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aptana for writing atlas script]]></title>
    <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/2006/08/24/aptana-for-writing-atlas-script/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-24T08:25:16+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flanders.co.nz/2006/08/24/aptana-for-writing-atlas-script</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I write quite a lot of javascript code these days and have been looking for a couple of months for ways to make my life easier.</p>

<p>Easier would mean in my opinion to get some kind of intellisense or autocomplete while writing javascript.</p>

<p>As it turns out in visual studio orcas these features will be available so I'll be a very happy vs orcas user i guess :).  But in the meantime there is a free eclipse based IDE around aptana that let's you take advantage of autocomplete etc.</p>

<p>I added the atlas debug files to the default code profile and I was in business.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[User group atlas presentations]]></title>
    <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/2006/08/11/user-group-atlas-presentations/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-11T08:53:16+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flanders.co.nz/2006/08/11/user-group-atlas-presentations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week I went to do a couple of presenations on atlas in the regional user groups here in New Zealand.</p>

<p>At first I was really nervous, so I apologise to the people in hamilton for not getting the best presenation I could give you, I even forgot some stuff that would make all the pieces fit together.</p>

<p>But after the first talk I started to get the hang of it, and now I regret that I can't do more talks but who knows what the future brings.</p>

<p>It was really interesting to see that there are a lot of really skilled people with a passion for programming in New Zealand.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>So in all I would like to thank everybody for taking the time to come and listen to my ramblings on Atlas.<br/>
And perhaps we'll meet on Teched next week.</p>

<p> </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
