<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Old Blog | Ivan Porto Carrero]]></title>
  <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/categories/old-blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/"/>
  <link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com"/>
  <updated>2012-04-22T21:10:37+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://flanders.co.nz/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ivan Porto Carrero]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Webresource.axd. How do I use it ???]]></title>
    <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/2006/01/04/webresourceaxd-how-do-i-use-it/"/>
    <updated>2006-01-04T19:53:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flanders.co.nz/2006/01/04/webresourceaxd-how-do-i-use-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever since I got my hands on .NET 2.0 I noticed the handler webresource.axd which seemed to provide a similar function as what I was using handlers for. </p>

<p>I used handlers in .NET 1.1 and before today also in .NET 2.0 to handle my javascript and css that I need in controls I developped. <br/>
I mark them before compiling as embedded resource and then later on read them out via reflection and they get served up by the browser.</p>

<p>I probably don't have to explain that (as long as your parameters don't change) this scripts get cached by the browser so they will only be downloaded once and re-used afterwards.</p>

<p>Well in asp.NET 2.0 there is a feature that uses webresource.axd to handle all kinds of embedded resources (images, pages, etc...)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.nikhilk.net/WebResourceAttribute.aspx">Nikhil Kothari </a>has a post on how to use them in <a href="http://www.nikhilk.net/WebResourceAttribute.aspx">his blog</a>, and I just copy pasted the text below.</p>

<p><strong><em>Using Web Resources<br/>
</em></strong>Imagine I am writing an HtmlEditor control and I want to use a stock bold button icon. Here's what I'd do:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Embed "Bold.gif" as a resource with the same name into my control's assembly.</p></li>
<li><p>Mark it as Web-accessible via the attribute:<br/>
<code>    [assembly: WebResource("Bold.gif", ContentType.ImageGif)]</code></p></li>
<li><p>Use the GetWebResourceUrl() method on Page to get a URL that can be rendered out to the client.<br/>
<code>    boldButton.ImageUrl = Page.GetWebResourceUrl(typeof(HtmlEditor), "Bold.gif");</code></p></li>
</ol>


<p>This results in a URL of the form:<br/>
<code>    WebResource.axd?a=MyControls&amp;r;=Bold.gif&amp;t;=632059604175183419</code></p>

<p><a href="http://www.pheedo.com/click.phdo?s=ws-58bab757b1982e63240738f517c2db883329859"><img src="http://www.pheedo.com/img.phdo?s=ws-58bab757b1982e63240738f517c2db883329859" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><img src="http://geekswithblogs.net/casualjim/aggbug/59980.aspx" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WebDav Exchange ... ]]></title>
    <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/2006/01/04/webdav-exchange/"/>
    <updated>2006-01-04T19:53:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flanders.co.nz/2006/01/04/webdav-exchange</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I live in new zealand.</p>

<p>I can successfully create appointments in exchange using webDAV.  But I can only create them in the timezone Z if I change the timezone to Y (which is mine) I always get bad request.</p>

<p>Do I say ok.. so not during string conversion but I just calculate the offset and add that to the date and create the appointment then that should be ok. Also not !!!</p>

<p>My conversion function is very basic but i didn't find a way to get it properly formatted in .NET so this is my way. The function below ends with “Y“ and this doesn't work, when I end it on Z it does work. Any suggestions ?</p>

<p>All sorted now.. instead of passing on the timezone I should replace the Y with the offset of the timezone to +13:00 in the new zealand case.</p>

<p>string</p>

<p>formatDate(DateTime input){</p>

<p>return input.ToString("yyyy-MM-ddTHH:mm:ss.fffzzz");<br/>
}</p>

<p>**** </p>

<p><a href="http://www.pheedo.com/click.phdo?s=ws-58bab757b1982e63240738f517c2db883329859"><img src="http://www.pheedo.com/img.phdo?s=ws-58bab757b1982e63240738f517c2db883329859" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><img src="http://geekswithblogs.net/casualjim/aggbug/63737.aspx" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Run VS 2k5 Webserver from everywhere]]></title>
    <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/2006/01/04/run-vs-2k5-webserver-from-everywhere/"/>
    <updated>2006-01-04T19:53:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flanders.co.nz/2006/01/04/run-vs-2k5-webserver-from-everywhere</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The built in webserver from Visual Studio 2005 is great for locally quickviewing asp.net websites.<br/>
I always thought it was a pitty that I had to start visual studio for it.</p>

<p>Today I came accross a blog of a guy who wrote a small shell extension so you can right-click any folder and choose run asp.net 2.0 website from the context menu. It will run the webserver on that folder. How easy do you want it ?</p>

<p>Read more about it here : <br/>
<a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/rmclaws/archive/2005/10/25/428422.aspx">http://weblogs.asp.net/rmclaws/archive/2005/10/25/428422.aspx</a><br/>
<a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/rmclaws/archive/2005/10/26/428600.aspx">http://weblogs.asp.net/rmclaws/archive/2005/10/26/428600.aspx</a></p>

<p>Download here :<br/>
<a href="http://www.interscapeusa.com/downloads/download.aspx?file=WebServerHere_v1.msi">http://www.interscapeusa.com/downloads/download.aspx?file=WebServerHere_v1.msi</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.pheedo.com/click.phdo?s=ws-58bab757b1982e63240738f517c2db883329859"><img src="http://www.pheedo.com/img.phdo?s=ws-58bab757b1982e63240738f517c2db883329859" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><img src="http://geekswithblogs.net/casualjim/aggbug/64042.aspx" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rss Parsing]]></title>
    <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/2006/01/04/rss-parsing/"/>
    <updated>2006-01-04T19:53:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flanders.co.nz/2006/01/04/rss-parsing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As mentioned earlier in this blog, I am building a rss program together with <a href="http://datafreakz.blogspot.com">http://datafreakz.blogspot.com</a></p>

<p>Right now we have about 100000 feeds from this feeds I had before the weekend about 5000 that failed. Now most of these feeds were valid rss although my google sidebar doesn't parse a lot of them either.</p>

<p>Then I've noticed that lots of people never took the time to read the specifications and dump whatever they like in an rss feed.<br/>
Furthermore there are a lot of people including w3c and ms that put stylesheets in their xml.  Up until last week (because I had a parser that seemed to parse a lot of it already), I was one of these people that thought that just using the System.Xml.XmlReader would be enough and that I would get everything on the first pass through my xml.</p>

<p>Now after the weekend I've figured out that it takes 3 passes, that is 3 different ways to get the xml in my program to parse almost everything. The next problem that shows up are feeds that do exist, but their hosts are pretty slow in resolving the domains etc.. so I will be needing some retry mechanism.  The idea behind our system is that we want to be able to parse <strong>every</strong> <strong>valid</strong> feed from the internet.</p>

<p>I've got the different encodings sorted now.</p>

<p>One of the feeds that bounces the first time :</p>

<p><a href="http://presscenter.org/repository/rss/nl/Ext_102110_5.xml">http://presscenter.org/repository/rss/nl/Ext_102110_5.xml</a></p>

<p>And this one doesn't want to parse yet :</p>

<p><a href="http://www.musicalfan.be/rssfeed.xml">http://www.musicalfan.be/rssfeed.xml</a></p>

<p>probably because of its description field in a few posts.  but I do read feeds with html in them that is what I find so strange.. I don't know why this one doesn't want to parse.. for now. ;-)</p>

<p>Always I will appreciate ideas.... I can't show you my code for my parsers but it is based on the xml reader class, too which you pass an encoded textreader. at least the first try parser.  I parse more feeds than Rss.NET and I parse more than rssbandit or rssfeeder.net But I want to be able to say that I parse about 99,99% of the feeds out there. <br/>
I don't want to use serialisation because of the performance overhead.. If you need to parse 100 000 - 300 000 feeds every bit counts ;)  And once we open up for the general public it will be even more feeds.</p>

<p>When everything will be finished online.. probably I will be providing a vs2k5 add in and outlook add in.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.pheedo.com/click.phdo?s=ws-58bab757b1982e63240738f517c2db883329859"><img src="http://www.pheedo.com/img.phdo?s=ws-58bab757b1982e63240738f517c2db883329859" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><img src="http://geekswithblogs.net/casualjim/aggbug/63483.aspx" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My vision on protecting your querystrings]]></title>
    <link href="http://flanders.co.nz/2006/01/04/my-vision-on-protecting-your-querystrings/"/>
    <updated>2006-01-04T19:53:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flanders.co.nz/2006/01/04/my-vision-on-protecting-your-querystrings</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://geekswithblogs.net/casualjim/articles/64639.aspx">http://geekswithblogs.net/casualjim/articles/64639.aspx</a></p>

<p> </p>

<p><a href="http://www.pheedo.com/click.phdo?s=ws-58bab757b1982e63240738f517c2db883329859"><img src="http://www.pheedo.com/img.phdo?s=ws-58bab757b1982e63240738f517c2db883329859" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><img src="http://geekswithblogs.net/casualjim/aggbug/64640.aspx" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
